

PROFILE

Web developer with a background in management and intellectual property law. Highly organised and valued team member with great interpersonal skills. Experienced at working under pressure to meet deadlines, and adept at finding technical solutions to problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript (ES6
- HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap
- Responsive Design
- React, React Native
- :• Node.js
- API configuration
- AWS, Heroku
- MongoDB, SQL, Firebase
- Git version control
- TDD (lest Cucumber)
- Chrome Dev Tools
- Postman
- Android Studio

Languages:

- English (native)
- German (B1)

CONTACT ME

Phone: 0049-178-6820851

Address: Nawiaskystr. 18, 81735 Munich.

Email: ianflemingdeveloper@gmail.com

Website: www.ianflemingdeveloper.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/i-fleming, Github: github.com/ianfleming464/ Music: ian-fleming.bandcamp.com/



IAN FLEMING

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Formalprozessabteilung Sachbearbeiter / Legal Assistant

Grünecker Patent- und Rechtsanswälte, Munich: May 2019-present

- Controlling and coordinating all formal processes relating to European Community and foreign designs, foreign trademarks. Reporting on publication/registration, invoicing, monitoring deferment deadlines, fee payment, ensuring accuracy and meticulous attention to detail in the face of multiple deadlines and a huge workload.
- Enhanced efficiency by overhauling, centralising and fully-digitising the fee payment/deferment schedule, in order to make it legible and understandable, ensuring no deadlines are missed in the event of absence, and to aid prioritisation of work.

Bar manager

The Keg Bar, Munich: March 2015 - March 2017

- Hired, trained and motivated staff to cultivate a a sense of team and a customer-focused approach, delegated work, meticulously planned drink/food orders depending on demand/upcoming events, showcased my adaptability by becoming and eagerness to learn by quickly earning a management role in an unfamiliar industry.
- Authored an extensive electronic staff handbook detailing every aspect of the job (from how to pour every drink/cocktail on the menu to how to deal with electrical faults in the building).

Book department worker, duty/weekend manager

The Book Centre, Waterford, Ireland: August 2008 - June 2014

- Analysed inventory and planned accordingly, ordering books for ca. 8 different sections to ensure we always had exactly what the customer wanted before they even knew they wanted it.
- Aggregated different rare title websites, so that we could safely say that, no matter how obscure or long out of print a title is, we could generally source it at a reasonable price.

EDUCATION

Career Foundry

Full-Stack Development Certificate, January 2020 - November 2020

- Attained a fluency in Javascript, and subsequently React, React Native and Node.js.
- Built a personal portfolio site from scratch to showcase my work, including:
- a fully-functional React Native chat app for Android and IOS, several apps that employ external APIs (including a Meetup app and a Pokedex clone) and notably an entire full-stack movie application (My 1980s Movies API) with login and user account functionality, creating using the MERN stack, the MVC design pattern and REST.

University College Limerick, Ireland

MA in Music Technology, 2012-2013

- Graduated with a 1.1
- Wrote a peer-reviewed scientific paper on a piece of music I composed and released, based on the voice of author Harlan Ellison ('I Have No Mouth (pts. 1-6) Introducing Postdigital Spectralism' Leonardo Music Journal LMJ24 p.45-48, Dec 2014 www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/abs/10.1162/LMJ_a_00201)

University College Cork, Ireland

BA in English and Sociology, 2000-2003